Alright, so our custom node is working successfully. Let's go ahead and create other node. So like we can create our add prefix and add suffix node as well. So we are going to first create our add prefix. So you can just simply write like this def add underscore prefix and in this again you have to provide like this state and then you have to type in as simple state. Alright, do you remember that this is something I told you that once you learn how to create this state.
these nodes then it is going to be super easy for you to follow along with this course. Throughout this course we will be creating so many nodes. We will be connecting all those nodes together. So it is very important to understand how these things are done. Alright, thereafter we have got our state. Again remember you can access any of the keys whatever these keys your state have. Input text, output text, whatever you want to access. You can access those keys.
inside your node whenever you want. So here I say that here is my current text. Or you can say the input text basically. So it is going to be like this. You have here current state. In fact current text. And thereafter we are going to actually prefix in our output text. So what I do here.
I can add just simply write a current text. So what we want to change this is. so I want to change this. So basically what I do here. So I say that. Hey, I have added something here. Alright. And then finally you can return this
output as usual. So it is going to... it is going to be something like this. Where you have your output underscore text and inside that you have your output. Perfect. It is going to be simple easy and super easy basically. Alright. Let's go ahead and copy this from here. We already have our state and if we execute this then see what happened here. This is add prefix here basically. Alright. So if you do like
this then what happened here. I just get here hey I have added something here. But we are not getting hello. Why? Because this process input is not executed. So our state is not modified like this. Currently we are having our state something like this. Inside this it has added this one. If you want to use this one as well. So basically if you want to follow along something like this. Then you have to first execute process input. Then whatever state comes there. Thereafter you have to execute the
Okay, add prefix. So now what I do here, after this add prefix, alright, then what I do, in fact before executing this add prefix, I have to make sure that I call this one. Alright, so inside this add prefix, I have to call the process input state. So it is going to return this and then it is going to be passed here and then finally it is going to give you the output.
In fact, this current text is not needed here, because we are working only on the output text.
Alright, let's go ahead and run this. And now you will notice here that, hey, I have added something and there is the hello here.
I can say that with some extra space. And then I execute this. I can say here that this is your prefix.
And then this is your hello, which is coming from the process input.
And again, remember here, inside this state, this add prefix, it is actually passing your output text only.
Input text is not passed here. Why? Because it is not currently being used as the line graph node.
Once we start using it as the line graph node, only then we will be having access to all these parameters.
Otherwise, if you print this here, something like this.
current state, I am going to say here that inside the add prefix.
So, you can monitor that. In fact, you can debug that. What is the current state here?
So, the current state inside this is coming output text only.
Remember this. And remember this. Once we build our final line graph,
then we will see that in this current state, we will be also seeing the input text because that is the
feature of the line graph, where it will maintain all the dictionary keys together.
But this is like a standard Python method. That is why whatever the dictionary we are passing inside this,
only those are getting printed here.
Alright. So, this is how you can write the add prefix.
Similarly, you can also write the add suffix as well. So, it is going to be super easy. Something like this.
Def add underscore suffix. Inside this it is going to be the state. And then finally, simple state. Super easy.
You see here that how easy it is. And then finally, I am going to say here again print. In fact, this whole thing I can copy from here.
And then I can just simply paste it here. And then I can see that inside the suffix what this state is going to be here.
Thereafter, I say here output equal to your state and then the output text. It is going to be like this.
And then I say here that with some something like this. Not like this. Yeah, something like this.
I have added suffix. Perfect. Let's go ahead and return this. And this return is going to be like this. Output text and then the output.
So, this is something which you have to match with your class. Basically, with your state.
Let's go ahead and run this. And if we call this whole things together. And thereafter, we call this add suffix here.
So, you see here what is happening here. This is like a nested function call. So, you execute this what happened.
First, it is going to call process input state. It is going to return hello in capital letter. Then it is going to add prefix.
Then it is going to add the suffix. Let's go ahead and run this and then see what happened here.
Prefix is having this one. And in the suffix, you are having this output. And then final output is coming like this.
Hey, I have added something here. Hello. This is coming from process input node. And then this is coming from the add suffix node.
You see that how easy and simple it is. The one thing it is missing here that is the input text. As I told you earlier that once you implement your lang graph then you will be able to see that it will also print the input text as well because the state will be maintained. In the lang graph what happen? As your code or you can say the application move from one node to another node there is a parameter which is known as a state.
So this state parameter is going to maintain all the states here. Alright. Between all these nodes together. Perfect. So this is all about in this lesson. In next lesson I will show you how you can create a simple graph. I will see you then.